PAULINE NARVAS



Website

https://paulinenarvas.com

Email Address pauline@paulinenarvas.com

Twitter

@paulienuh

LinkedIn

pnarvas

GitHub nawlean

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Solutions Architect Associate (SAA) Amazon Web Services

December 2020

AWS Cloud Practitioner (CCP)

November 2019

AWS

Amazon Web Services

COMMUNITY ROLES

Ladies in DevOps Community Founder Code First: Girls Brand Ambassador

Girls Community
Brand Builder

EDUCATION

& Instructor

The University of Sheffield

BSc Biomedical Sciences with Employment Experience

(September 2014 - June 2018) 2.1

Tapton School

12 A*-C GCSEs including Maths, English and Triple Science, 3 A Levels: Biology (B), Chemistry (A), Sociology (A*)

(September 2008 -September 2014)

SKILLS

HTML CSS lavascript Reactis Nextjs **Pvthon** Wordpress **AWS Terraform** Kubernetes Chef Ansible Docker **Public speaking** Community Blogging Building **Content Creation Podcasting**

AWARDS

Finalist in "Rising Star of the Year -Large Organisations"

Computing Rising Star Awards (2020)

301 Female Tech Trailblazers

Business Cloud (2018)

Ones to Watch

Code First: Girls (2018)

Most influential student in the UK - 5th place

The Tab & J.P Morgan (2018)

Finalist as "Best Intern"

National Undergraduate Employability Awards (2018)

PROFILE

Equipped with strong technical and communication skills built from 3+ years in the tech industry, 4+ years developing communities (Code First: Girls, Ladies in DevOps & AWS Community Builder) and 10+ years building an online presence on pawlean.com.

My technical expertise expands from modern web development to DevOps and Cloud engineering. I'm also AWS Certified. With self-development at the centre of my character, I'm continuously eager to grow in my skills and knowledge to be the best technical leader that I can be.

EXPERIENCE

gitpod

Senior Community Engineer

(July 2021 - Present)

- Driving adoption of gitpod across different technical communities
- Building our core open source community
- Outreach and advocacy of gitpod (developer education)
- Taking feedback from communities to improve developer experience

Sky Betting & Gaming

DevOps Engineer

(January 2021 - July 2021)

- Developing infrastructure as code onto on-prem and Cloud environments
- Supporting the day-to-day operations of virtual machines and containers for squads across the Bet Tribe
- Building the resilience, scalability, reliability of our platform
- Tech used: Kubernetes, Chef, Akamai, Jenkins, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Linux

BT

Digital Engineering Graduate & Site Reliability Engineer

(September 2018 - December 2020)

Two year graduate scheme, four six month rotations within BT Consumer Digital. In August 2020, I rolled off the scheme as a Site Reliability Engineer.

Site Reliability Engineer, SRE Squad (March 2020 - December 2020)

- Contributed to development of the new SRE team, driving the team's long-term vision and advocating our value. This raised our profile across BT Group and externally, gaining backing from higher management and a speaking slot at SRECON20.
- Contributed to the development of our cloud computing standards striving for operational excellence across BT. Focusing on optimizing cost, performance, reliability, and security.
- Drove a 21% decrease in our CIS security issues and saved \$250K annual costs on our production accounts.
- Reduced TOIL, using AWS Lambda, scripting, automated manual tasks

DevOps Engineer, Platform Services (September 2019 - March 2020)

- Standardised BT Consumer Digital's delivery pipeline for cloud infrastructure provisioning and development CI/CD workflows, promoting a consistent approach on our infrastructure.
- Assisted squads in integrations with our CI/CD e.g. Jenkins
- Advocated Platform Services and the power of our tools to speed up releases into production
- Led the Single Sign On (SSO) project delivery and implementation for Slack with Jenkins and Shibboleth for BT Enterprise. Transforming the way colleagues collaborate with each other.

Software Engineer, MyEE Web (March 2019 - September 2019)

- Contributed to several scheduled production releases for MyEE Web including building new UI features on the Roaming and Add-ons page
- Prioritised discussions to improve the User Experience for the 10 million customers registered on MyEE
- Led in prioritising technical debt including refactoring projects which helped keep our large codebase clean
- Developed Proof of Concepts that improved our current approach on automation and current tech stack

Digital Solutions Architect, Digital Architecture (September 2018 - March 2019)

- Worked with stakeholders from impacted squads to gather key requirements of propositions
- Produced impact assessments with new propositions to present at the Digital IA forum
- Identified ways we can improve our digital tools, technology and architecture
- Involvement in the working group that looked at simplifying enterprise tooling strategy
 to better our ways of working This led to the implementation of Slack which is now used
 as the primary internal communication tool

Notable contributions

- Led the technical implementation of "Code Bootcamp" a React app where graduates can learn to code
- Featured in BT's rebrand campaign, "Beyond Limits" on their promo video
- Featured in The Yorkshire Post, The Daily Mirror, The Sheffield Star to share my career iourney
- Organised a "Techy Tea party" with Leeds Library to help grow essential digital skills for the general public
- Organised a BT Hack Day with the University of Leeds to promote BT's new technical direction and inspire innovation in students